<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: IELTS | Raven's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.iraven.ch/post/categories/ielts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.iraven.ch/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-25T16:19:59+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.iraven.ch/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raven Chen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charity special days]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.iraven.ch/post/2013/12/25/charity-special-days/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-25T16:15:02+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.iraven.ch/post/2013/12/25/charity-special-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is an essay written in practicing for the IELTS test writing module.</em></p>

<p>Special days, such as National Children&rsquo;s Day and National Anti-Smoking Day, have been established and advertised by some charitable organizations across the globe, which is a rather common form employed to promote cultural or religious ideas.</p>

<p>In order for such ideas or visions to be effectively promoted to the general public and in the end achieve their designed goals, it is required for the advertising methods to be both economical to carry out and able to persist a long-lasting influence on societies. Since most charities are operating under public or private fund and limited resources, it would be economically wiser to take on roles of inspiring people, instead of getting involved in each one of the detailed operations, sending staffs on the street to talk each smoking person out of the habit would not be that cost-efficient for example. Holidays, or special days, on the other hand, once adopted, requires no further costs from charities. Those who are convinced of the ideas would come out preach, and those who have been sharing the similar ones would be attracted and join the parade.</p>

<p>Through out the entire human history, special days has been observed within almost every culture and proven to be quite effective, due to the facts that they can be easily remembered and practiced and useful on attracting public attention. Human is a creature of habit, which, once formed, is rather hard to be unlearnt. Also, because most of the special days are oftentimes associated with some historical or public major event occurred on a specific date, which will constantly be reminded with later on, it is not hard for the public to remember and relate to. Even though some special days were started out and only held seriously by a few minority groups, once the values behind them have been recognized, it would not be impossible for them to attract the government&rsquo;s or media&rsquo;s attention to further promote the ideas to broader audiences.</p>

<p>In general, I think it is a smart move for charities to rely on special days for making their visions known and keeping them alive, both efficiently and effectively.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working too much and having no time for families and friends]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.iraven.ch/post/2013/12/24/working-too-much-and-having-no-time-for-families-and-friends/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-24T16:43:17+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.iraven.ch/post/2013/12/24/working-too-much-and-having-no-time-for-families-and-friends</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is an essay written in practicing for the IELTS test writing module.</em></p>

<p>In today&rsquo;s ever demanding yet opportunity-rich society, people tend to focus too much on their work, rather than spending enough time with their families and friends.</p>

<p>Admittedly, the major cause of this phenomenon is that our working environment is becoming increasingly competitive, due to the progress of modernization and globalization. As information flowing more freely and transparently, it becomes much harder for business to keep a competitive advantage over its rivals. Without even approaching any form of commercial espionage, a simple Google search might just yield enough results regarding solutions about how to cut down operational cost, new market angles to generate fresh revenue, accessible technologies to boost productivity, etc. Competitions drive down prices, force companies into cost reductions and working people nowadays have to either work longer hours to get enough pay or invest more time into improving their employability. Many other reasons, such as global project collaboration which requires long-distance traveling, also contribute to longer time spent away from family and friends.</p>

<p>This trend has a two-way impacts on our society. On the up side, hard working increases social wealth and further enriches individuals' life. Increased social wealth means more tax incomes for the government, thus more money could be spending on improving education, building better infrastructure and covering public welfare, which could eventually be translated into a happier and more productive society. While on the down side, working too hard and not paying enough attention to family members could severely weaken family bonds. Children growing up in such families often show less respect to others and have higher rates of committing crimes, comparing to those from well-bonded families. Also, without frequent communication with friends, it is easy for adults to build up stress, inducing bad tempers and various psychological or physical health issues. All of which decrease the overall stability of our society.</p>

<p>Personally, I enjoy working hard and creatively in order to fulfill my potentials, and I also prefer to keep a proper work-life balance. Hopefully, more people will start realizing that work, families and friends are all crucial parts of our life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
